WILMER RIVERA

Rome, GA

Phone: 706-331-4752 | Email: coding706@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/wilmer88 | Portfolio: https://wilmer88.github.io/blast-porfolio/ |

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/wilmer-rivera-0536291b3

SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer experienced working with Linux/Ubuntu, Windows and MACos, setting up different IDEs with various code editors like IntelliJ, Visual Studio and VS Code. Actively taking Pluralsight OO design patterns. Strongly committed to building reliable maintainable code using any framework. Successfully refactor projects to be used with new version releases. Led all planning and designing of Coat & Code web applications and projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Softwares/Platforms: Django, Laravel, React, NoSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, AWS, Oracle, Git,

JQuery, Node, handlebars.

Software Languages: ES6, JavaScript, Python, Java, PHP, C#, HTML5, CSS, C++

PROJECTS

taco-stand | github.com/wilmer88/taco-stand | https://taco-stand.herokuapp.com

- Gives business a template to sell their products, where foodies can pre order and make
 online payments, eliminating having to wait in line and the inevitable prepping wait time
 that comes after placing an order; help to eliminates the need to use man/ woman power
 to take orders and receive payments; vanishes all check delivery times, since paid orders
 are instantly available to kitchen staff.
- Solely responsible for the application idea, the building of all features; in charge of creating, designing and finding solutions, also for writing all of the backend and frontend source code and launching the application.
- Technologies used: React/JSX, React Router, Express, Node, MongoDB, Bulma, ES6, Bcrypt, JWT, Mongoose, Axios, Stripe Checkout, JSON Web Token and more, please see dependencies.

Web-Inventory | github.com/wilmer88/tool-inventory | https://tool-inventory.herokuapp.com

- App enables employees' mobile devices to document items, their location, count, specifications, and the name of the employee that was assigned to count those items, facilitating a speedy and accurate inventory count.
- Singly responsible for inception of application by writing all the source code, creating the front end design, doing all testing, building all the features and finally launching the app.
- Built with Foundation css framework, Handlebars, HTML, JawsDB MySQL and Sequelize.

ga_dev | github.com/wilmer88/err-help | https://ga-devs1.herokuapp.com

- Full CRUD application where jr developers can post their computer errors and solutions. Created for developers to save their solutions, their knowledge and ask "dumb questions" all connected to a live database. Works well on desktop, with mobile responsiveness. Future development is pending until further notice.
- Lone creator of all backend and frontend code, the view all tab functionality, both edit and delete page functionalities are done. Please see my portfolio for my other projects.
- Project uses: Bootstrap, Django/MVC/ORM, SQLite3, pgAdmin, AWS, and Heroku.

EXPERIENCE

Owner

2020 - Present

Coat & Code LLC

Rome, Woodbine Ave

In charge of giving a price for job bids, budgeting and negotiating counter offers, analyzing and comparing offers to other alike jobs, for price matching; ensuring fair market price for both client Coat & Code. In charge of keeping communication with clients to better understand clients needs and expectations. Responsible for finished job quality and scheduling after job completion.

Generalist

2013 - 2020

MCC LLC

Rome, GA

Pipeline maintenance company that offers terminals, right of way and tank farms services. Was responsible for crew, equipment, trailers, transportation and equipment rentals. Driving different company box trucks, ordering and purchasing project materials and tools. Sandblasting, shoveling; painting underground lines on right of way, also doing interior construction, warehouse tasks and many other jobs and responsibilities. Gain massive respect when several property owners would go out of their way and hand write letters to the project manager, letting him know how happy and impressed they were with our work and how we went above and beyond expectations.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology: Atlanta, GA

2020 - 2020

An 18 week intensive Full Stack Flex Web Development Certification focused on gaining skills in frontend and backend web development, industry best practices. The creating, connecting to, and working with databases; maintaining legacy code, computer science fundamentals, API architecture, PWA for increased application performance, test driven driven development and much more.